

# CONTACT

+421 917 968 638

Web Site

blabuda@gmail.com

Martin, Slovakia

# SKILLS

Blue Prism

VB.NET

C# (in training)

WPF

MS SQL / TSQL

Python + Streamlit

UlPath (in training)

# SOFT SKILLS

Analytical thinking
Problem solving
Eagerness to learn
Independence
Team player

Responsibility

# **Boris Labuda**

# Senior RPA Developer

#### PROFILE

I am a dedicated **Automation and Software Developer** with over **22 years of experience in the manufacturing industry**, delivering software and process automation solutions. My expertise spans **Blue Prism**, **VB.NET**, **WPF**, **and ADO.NET**, with a focus on modernizing legacy systems, creating visualization dashboards, and optimizing complex business processes. Role of **IT manager** gave me experience with scaling and running core IT services and chance to collaborate with external partners across all regions. Passionate about **continuous learning**, I am currently **expanding into C# (.NET)** for cross-platform support, **UIPath** (Associate developer level) for intelligent process automation .

# PROFESSIONAL HIGHLIGHTS

- Reduced Blue Prism licensing costs by 50% by developing a custom solution for scheduling and resource allocation, replacing the native Blue Prism Control Room functionality.
- Saved 200+ work hours weekly by designing and deploying a global automation solution for shoe costing integrating Blue Prism, SQL, SQL databases, and .NET applications.
- Delivered 20+ automation projects and 20+ internal .NET Framework applications focused on streamlining and accelerating business processes.
- Built a strong local IT department and introduced innovative IT support processes, which were repeatedly recognized by the parent company.

# KEY PROJECTS

#### **Process Automation (Blue Prism)**

- Developed a custom dynamic scheduling and planning system fully replacing the native Blue Prism Scheduler. The solution consists of a .NET application for resource management and dynamic scheduling, and a Windows Service for orchestration and automation triggering.
- Delivered a global automation solution for footwear costing, integrating Blue Prism, SAP SQL DB, and .NET applications for data management. Successfully implemented across 7 manufacturing units worldwide.
- Implemented 20+ additional automation solutions across logistics, planning, and finance domains.

# LANGUAGES

#### EDUCATION

University of Žilina 1997-2002

Master's Degree Operations and Economics of Railway Transport

#### HOBBIES



#### .NET Framework Development

- Developed WPF applications for real-time visualization of performance metrics and production planning in a manufacturing environment.
- Created an internal intranet portal using VB.NET, ASP.NET, MS SQL, and SAP ERPConnect, enabling centralized access to enterprise data and improving internal communication.
- Developed and implemented a just-in-time material supply planning system for production lines, integrating VB.NET applications with PLCs and SAP, ensuring efficient and timely material flow.

#### AI & Data Visualization

- Developed a chatbot for natural language SQL querying, enabling non-technical users to interact with databases conversationally.
- Created experimental projects focused on AI agents and data visualization.

# EXPERIENCE

# Senior Process Automation Developer

ECCO Sko AS / Martin, Slovakia Oct 2019 - Present

- Acting as Senior developer and Technical architect for Blue Prism
- Development of automations for areas of logistics, finance and production on both, local and global scale.
- Mentoring junior developer team members.
- Creating and implementing Blue Prism development best practices.
- Investigating and preparing POC for possible AI LLM integration, currently in OpenAI, LangChain / Python + Streamlit.

# IT Manager

ECCO Slovakia/ Martin, Slovakia June 2010 - Sep 2019

- Led a team of 4 IT specialists, managing infrastructure for 200+ users.
- Directed and executed strategic IT projects, ensuring IT service availability and scalability.
- Oversaw IT budgeting, vendor relationships, procurement, and licensing.
- Built and maintained .NET-based local applications for visualization of productivity and efficiency of production processes.

#### ■ IT & SAP User Support

ECCO Slovakia/ Martin, Slovakia 2004 - 2010

# Production Planner

ECCO Slovakia/ Martin, Slovakia 2002 - 2004